Finding Aid for Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (University of Michigan) Publications, 1937-ongoing
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (University of Michigan) publications 1937-[ongoing], 1970-1990
University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.
2 linear feet
9732; Bimu; C146; 2
Teaching and research unit the College of Engineering of the University of Michigan. Contains published materials produced by or for the department and its subunits including annual reports, histories, newsletters, bulletins, proceedings,and student publications.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the unit (donor no. 6717 ) and the College of Engineering (donor no. 1884 ).
The publications are open for research.
Please consult the history found in the manuscript finding aid which precedes the publications finding aid.
The Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Publications are divided into four series: Unit Publications, Sub-Unit Publications, Topical Publications and Student Publications. The bulk of the publications document the department and its various laboratories.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Solid State Electronics Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering.; University of Michigan. Radiation Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Advanced Computer Architecture Laboratory.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.; Cooley Electronics Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Electron Physics Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Information Systems Laboratory.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Electrical Engineering.; University of Michigan. Solid State Electronics Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Radiation Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Advanced Computer Architecture Laboratory.; University of Michigan. Artificial Intelligence Laboratory.; Cooley Electronics Laboratory.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Pamphlets.; Bulletins.; Histories.; Newsletters.; Proceedings.; Programs.; Reports.; Student publications.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
  The Unit Publications series contains annual reports, brochures, bulletins, flyers, histories, newsletters, posters, proceedings, programs, reports, and textbooks. The annual reports document the activities of the department from 1967 to 1979 and contain summaries of departmental research for this time period. The brochures describe the department from 1957 to 1995 and an undated pamphlet chronicles the development of ENIAC. The bulletins document the department from 1988 to 1997. There is a department directory included in the 1990 volume. The researcher will find several departmental histories, including The Department of Electrical Engineering: A 75-Year History, which was written to commemorate the seventy-fifth anniversary of the department. In addition there is a long run, from 1979 to 1991, of the weekly internal newsletter Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Newsletter. The Communicator is the department's annual newsletter for alumni, students and staff. The Bentley Historical Library holds issues of this publication from 1992 to 1994. The proceedings are from a seminar honoring Professor William G. Dow in 1964. The researcher will find various reports, as well as two textbooks by Richard K. Brown which were published by the department.
  - Annual Reports
    - Annual Research Review, 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Annual Research Summary, 1982/83 (Box 1)
    - Electrical Engineering Research, 1967-1971, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Electrical and Computer Engineering Research, 1971-1979, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Computer Engineering, 1973/74-1982/83 (Box 1)
    - ENIAC: Electronic Numerical Integrator and Computer, undated (Box 1)
    - Electrical Engineering, 1957-1991, undated (Box 1)
    - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 1991-1995, undated (Box 1)
    - Graduate Studies in..., 1977-1978, undated (Box 1)
    - Graduate study in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Department 1984-1986 and undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, includes description of EECS Building 1977-1978, undated (Box 1)
  - Bulletins
    - Computer Science and Engineering: Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, includes Department Directory, 1990, 1999, and undated (Box 1)
    - Graduate Study in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
    - Microwave Science and Engineering, undated (Box 1)
    - Robotics Research and Education at the University of Michigan, undated (Box 1)
  - Flyers
    - Miscellaneous undated (Box 1)
  - Histories
    - A Brief History of the Department of Electrical Engineering [of the] University of Michigan, 1944 (Box 1)
    - The Department of Electrical Engineering: A 75-Year History, 1895-1970, 1970 (Box 1)
    - History of the Electrical Engineering Department, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Communicator: Annual Publications of the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
    - Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Newsletter, 1979-1991, 11 folders (Box 1)
    - EECS Computing Services Newsletter, 1986 (Box 1)
    - EECS News, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Posters
    - Miscellaneous undated (Box 1)
  - Proceedings
    - New Research Frontiers in Physical Electronics: Proceedings of a Recognition Seminar in Honor of Professor William G. Dow, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Programs
    - Conferences and Symposia 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - Utilization of Monopolar Crossed-Field-Neutralized Plasmas for Power Generation by Controlled Nuclear Fusion by W.G. Dow, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Workshop
      - New Directions in System Science and Engineering, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Textbooks
    - Linear Programmed Instruction Notes on An Introduction to the Sinusoidal Steady-State by R.K. Brown, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Notes for ECE-427 Electroacoustics by Richard K. Brown, 1983 (Box 2)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit.
  The Sub-Unit Publications series includes publications from the Advanced Computer Architecture Laboratory, Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, Computer Information and Control Engineering, the College Electronics Laboratory, the Electron Physics Laboratory, the Information Systems Laboratory, Optical Sciences, the Radiation Laboratory, the Radio Astronomy Observatory, the Robotics Industrial Affiliates Program, the Solid-State Electronics Laboratory, the Solid-State Industrial Affiliates Program, and the Systems Engineering Laboratory. The Cooley Electronics Laboratory published annual reports between 1976 and 1979, as well as brochures and manuals. The Cooley Laboratory continues the work of the Electronic Defense Group, a body formed in 1951 to carry out classified military research. The Sub-Units Publications also includes an abstract and report from the Electron Physics Laboratory in the 1960s. There are reports dating from the 1960s by the Information Systems Laboratory. The Solid-State Electronics Laboratory publications include undated brochures, a bulletin containing faculty biographies and a 1987 program from the dedication of the EECS building. There are three reports from the Systems Engineering Laboratory dated from the 1960s.
  - Advanced Computer Architecture Laboratory
    - Proposals
      - Proposal for Coordinated Experimental Research on Highly Parallel Computing, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Artificial Intelligence Laboratory
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
    - Bulletins
      - The University of Michigan's Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, undated (Box 2)
  - Computer Information and Control Engineering
    - Brochures 1972-1973, undated (Box 2)
    - Bulletins
      - Graduate Studies in Computer Information and Control Engineering, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Cooley Electronics Laboratory
    - Annual Reports 1977-1979 (Box 2)
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
    - Manuals
      - Guide to Technical Reports Preparation, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Reports
      - An Algorithm for Concurrent Random Walks on Highly Parallel Computers by R.F. Rosin, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Electron Physics Laboratory
    - Abstracts
      - Programs and Abstracts for Program Review Meeting, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Reports
      - Solid-State Materials and Devices: Semiannual Progress Report, no. 1, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Information Systems Laboratory
    - Reports
      - An Analysis of Errors in Finite Automata by Philip S. Dauber, 1965 (Box 2)
      - Covering Problems: Duality Relations and a New Method of Solution by Eugene L. Lawler, 1965 (Box 2)
      - A Study of a Model for Parallel Computation by Raymond Reiter, 1965 (Box 2)
      - A Study of Iterative Circuit Computers, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Optical Sciences
    - Bulletins undated (Box 2)
    - Programs 1989 (Box 2)
  - Radiation Laboratory
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
  - Radio Astronomy Observatory
    - Brochures 1968 (Box 2)
  - Robotics Industrial Affiliates Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
  - Solid-State Electronics Laboratory
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
    - Bulletins, includes faculty biographies undated (Box 2)
    - Programs 1987 (Box 2)
  - Solid-State Industrial Affiliates Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 2)
  - Systems Engineering Laboratory
    - Reports
      - Computer Programs Dealing with Finite-State Machines: Part I by Thomas F. Piatkowski, 1967 (Box 2)
      - Errors in Finite Automata by Phillips S. Dauber, 1965 (Box 2)
      - Initiation Timing in a Model for Parallel Computation by Raymond Reiter, 1966 (Box 2)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series includes printed materials published to document specific events or activities such as fund-raising or one-time conferences hosted by the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. This series includes a program from the Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers Antennas and Propagation Society International Symposium that was held in Ann Arbor in 1993. The Information Theory Group of the IEEE also held a symposium in Ann Arbor in 1986. The abstract of their meeting is found in this series.
  - Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers
    - Antennas and Propagation Society International Symposium
      - Programs 1993 (Box 2)
    - Information Theory Group
      - Abstracts
        - International Symposium on Information Theory, 1986 (Box 2)
- Student Publications
  The Student Publications series contains publications published by student groups within the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. The Student Publications series includes EECS Speaks is a joint publication of the student groups Eta Kappa Nu and the Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers. The Bentley Historical Library holds this publication from 1988 to 1999 and 2001 to the present. This series also includes the 1968 report, Electromyographically Controlled Orthotic Hand from the Student Design Project.
  - Newsletters
    - EECS Speaks
      - 1988-1999 (Box 2)
      - 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Student Design Project
    - Reports
      - Electromyographically Controlled Orthotic Hand, 1968 (Box 2)